in this video we're going to take a look
at posting setup in GP and compare that
to the experience of defining posting
groups in business
Central setting up default posting
accounts in GP helps simplify and reduce
errors and inconsistencies when posting
transactions once the accounts are set
up they will default on transaction
entry
windows in this example in the posting
account setup window we have defined
accounts for all default accounts
including the accounts reable
account if I go to one of the customers
in GP I can see that the customer is
assigned to a specific class and in that
class we have categorized those
transactions posted from customers in
this class to use a different accounts
receivable account and then in rare
cases you can Define more granularity
and entering unique accounts for
individual customers similar logic can
be applied to vendors and
items now let's look at business Central
and how we configure posting accounts
and Define
defaults business Central uses posting
groups to tie customers vendors and
items to GL accounts there are several
different types of posting groups in
business Central Business posting groups
focus on who you are buying and selling
to product posting groups focus on what
you are buying and
selling let's take a closer look
in the business posting groups you can
group Master data like customers into
regions segments Industries or however
your business wants to categorize sales
and purchases for
reporting product posting groups again
focus on what you sell or buy here you
may distinguish on product line or by
use for manufacturing retail or
Services posting setup is where you pull
these two concept steps together
combining the what with the
who in this
example we are indicating who are
Enterprise customers with the what which
is equipment and then we can Define
sales cost of good sold account and
other relevant
accounts now let's look at a customer
and see where we can assign these
posting
groups on my customer card I can see I
assigned the Enterprise General business
posting group and the customer posting
group of Northeast the customer group is
where you define your AR and discount
accounts here we have organized our
customers by region similar to the
classes we defined in
GP now let's create a sales invoice and
see how the accounts all get defaulted
onto transactions
similar to the customer posting groups
all items also have an inventory posting
group in the inventory posting group is
where you can Define accounts based on
item
classification and
location finally let's preview posting
for the invoice so we can see the GL
accounts that will be used when posting
we can see the inventory account is
pulled from the inventory posting group
we just saw the cost of good sold and
sales accounts are being pulled from
posting setup where we Define the what
from the product posting group and the
who from General business posting
finally the accounts receivable account
from my customer posting group that
looks similar to my customer class
accounts from
GP and that's a look at how posting
groups can be set up in business Central
with similar posting outcomes as
GP to learn more about business Central
see the following resources